aa<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ncaa.com/newsrss" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>www.ncaa.com</title>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/newsrss</link>
    <description>All Sports</description>
    <category>all</category>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://ncaa.com/newsrss" rel="self"></atom:link>
        
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[No. 11 Saint Michael's tops conference rival Saint Anslem with 13-5 victory]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="inline-left photo">
	<img src="/sites/default/files/images/finalQuenneville.jpg" />
	<div class="photo-caption">
		Quenneville</div>
</div>
<div>
	<p>
		<strong>COLCHESTER, Vt. --</strong>&nbsp; No. 2 Saint Michael&#39;s recorded its sixth consecutive victory with a 13-5 win against Saint Anselm in Northeast-10 Conference action on Wednesday at Duffy Field. The Purple Knights improved to 7-2 overall and 6-0 in league, while the Hawks fell to 2-7 and 2-5.</p>
</div>
<p>
	Senior Pete Donnally scored five goals for Saint Michael&#39;s. Classmate Max Zuccarni notched three goals and an assist, while junior Tim McDonald had a pair of markers. Junior Cooper Quenneville totaled a goal, two assists and four ground balls, senior Marty Vanzo finished with a goal and an assist, and classmate Asa Sargent scored a goal.</p>
<p>
	Sophomore Luke Solms recorded career highs of six ground balls and six caused turnovers, while junior Chris Casserly notched five ground balls and went 7-for-13 on draws. Senior Evan White and junior Sean Smith each picked up four ground balls, and junior Chris DeMairo made 11 saves.</p>
<p>
	Sophomore Geoff Kennedy finished with a goal and an assist for Saint Anselm, while senior James Brine scored a goal and had four ground balls. Junior Jake Mallinson and sophomores Andy Budz and James Peters picked up a goal apiece. Junior Andrew Messner posted two assists. Junior Matthew Steele totaled seven ground balls and won 10 face-offs, while senior Jonathon O&#39;Reilly stopped eight shots.</p>
<p>
	Donnally and Sargent scored consecutive goals for the Purple Knights in the opening 5:56 before the Hawks tallied with 7:46 remaining in the first to cut the hosts&#39; advantage to one. Zuccarini added a man-up goal with 5:45 left in the quarter, and Donnally scored with 1:10 to play to extend the Saint Michael&#39;s lead to 4-1 after one.</p>
<p>
	After Saint Anselm scored 2:29 into the second period, the Purple Knights netted the next five goals during a 5:58 stretch to increase their advantage to 9-2. The Hawks converted three of the next four goals to move to within five, but Saint Michael&#39;s notched three tallies in the final frame while holding the visitors scoreless.</p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/lacrosse-men/article/2013-04-10/no-11-saint-michaels-tops-conference-rival-saint-anslem-13-5-vi</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-mens/lacrosse-men">lacrosse-men</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d2">d2</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/saint-anselm-college">Saint Anselm College</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/saint-michaels-college">Saint Michael&#039;s College</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 01:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>gmcmillen</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">173127 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Mississippi State defeats third top-20 foe in a row with win against LSU]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="inline-left photo">
	<img src="/sites/default/files/images/finalWhite(1).jpg" />
	<div class="photo-caption">
		White</div>
</div>
<div>
	<p>
		<strong>BATON ROUGE, La. --</strong> For the first time since 2005, Mississippi State (16-7, 6-5 SEC) has downed three consecutive top-20 opponents, as the Bulldogs defeated No. 20 LSU (13-10, 4-7 SEC) 4-1 on Wednesday. With the win, State has won its last four matches against the Tigers, including a 7-0 victory earlier this season.</p>
</div>
<p>
	The win continues what has been an impressive road showing for State this spring, improving to 6-0 in away matches.</p>
<p>
	State took the early lead Wednesday by grabbing the doubles point. On court three, the two teams traded holds until the MSU duo of Pedro Dumont and Ethan Wilkinson earned a break to go up 6-5, eventually defeating LSU&rsquo;s Boris Arias and Tam Trinh 8-6.</p>
<p>
	The State tandem of Jordan Angus and Malte Stropp, ranked 12th in the nation, went up a break to start and then earned another break later in the match to go up 6-3. The Tigers&rsquo; No. 52 team of Chris Simpson and Stefan Szacinski earned a break and then a hold to come within one, but Angus and Stropp held strong to take the match 8-6, clinching the doubles point for State. Play on court two was suspended at that point, with LSU&rsquo;s Roger Anderson and Olivier Borsos leading MSU&rsquo;s Romain Bogaerts and Zach White 7-6.</p>
<p>
	In singles, tiebreakers were the determinant for the first set on four courts. After the teams had traded first sets on courts two and five, the Bulldogs claimed three of the breakers (two by 8-6 scores), capturing four of the six first sets in the process.  </p>
<p>
	White was the most dominant point of the day, only dropping two games en route to defeating LSU&rsquo;s Arias 6-2, 6-0 on court five for a 2-0 MSU lead. On court six, Dumont battled to take the first-set tiebreaker 7-6(4) and then cruised to victory in the second set, downing the Tigers&rsquo; Harrison Kennedy 7-6(4), 6-1, pushing MSU&#39;s lead to 3-0.   </p>
<p>
	LSU&rsquo;s lone point of the day came on court two, as No. 104 Szacinski upended MSU&rsquo;s No. 58 Stropp 6-3, 6-4.</p>
<p>
	The Bulldogs then clinched the match thanks to senior James Chaudry who, after taking a first-set tiebreaker 7-6(6), found his groove in the second, blasting LSU&rsquo;s Borsos to win 7-6(6), 6-0 and hand the Bulldogs the win.</p>
<p>
	Play on courts one and four were suspended once the match was clinched, with MSU freshman No. 12 Bogaerts leading 7-6(6), 2-3 against LSU&rsquo;s No. 51 Simpson at the top spot and LSU&rsquo;s Mark Bowtell leading MSU&rsquo;s Angus 7-6(1), 1-3 at No. 4.  </p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/tennis-men/article/2013-04-10/mississippi-state-defeats-third-top-20-foe-row-win-against-lsu</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-mens/tennis-men">tennis-men</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d1">d1</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/louisiana-state-university">Louisiana State University</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/mississippi-state-university">Mississippi State University</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>gmcmillen</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">173119 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[No. 2 Dickinson holds off comback by Gettysburg for 12-10 victory]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="inline-left photo">
	<img src="/sites/default/files/images/finalGleason.jpg" />
	<div class="photo-caption">
		Gleason</div>
</div>
<div>
	<p>
		<strong>GETTYSBURG, Pa. --</strong> No. 2 Dickinson jumped out to a big lead on Gettysburg and held off a late rally by the Bullets to remain unbeaten on the season with a 12-10 victory at the Battlefield.</p>
</div>
<p>
	The Bullets struck first, taking a 1-0 lead at the 9:46 mark on a goal by Martin Manilla. The Red Devils capitalized on a couple of Gettysburg penalties to answer with five consecutive goals to take a 5-1 lead at the end of the first quarter.</p>
<p>
	Junior Parker Waldron put the Devils on the board at the 7:44 mark to pull Dickinson even. Classmate Brian Gleason tallied back-to-back goals, finishing an assist from Brian Cannon and scoring a transition goal with an assist from long pole midfielder Brandon Palladino.</p>
<p>
	Nick Leon stretched the margin to 4-1 with an extra-man goal, scoring with just 28 seconds on the clock. The Devils won the ensuing face-off and Cannon scored with 11 seconds to play in the quarter.</p>
<p>
	Brett Parker scored off an assist from Will Scott, and Carter Moore won the face-off and scored just six seconds later to give Dickinson an 7-1 advantage with 12:40 to play in the half.</p>
<p>
	Cannon tallied another to put the Devils up 8-1 before a three-goal run by the Bullets cut the deficit to 8-4 at halftime.</p>
<p>
	The teams played scoreless through most of the third quarter before the Devils tallied a pair behind goals from Gleason and senior Matt Cherry, scoring in a span of just 27 seconds.</p>
<p>
	Palladino added another assist to Gleason and was looking for another off a face-off, following a Gettysburg goal with 1:29 remaining in the period to make the score 10-5 heading into the final quarter.</p>
<p>
	Leon opened the fourth with a goal from Leon as he finished an assist from first-year Chris Menard at the 13:58 mark. The Bullets countered at the 11:46 mark, capitalizing on a fast break.</p>
<p>
	Palladino had an opportunity to score with less than six minutes to play, dodging into the space on a clear save by Jon Maddalone, who turned the shot away.</p>
<p>
	Jimmy Morris tallied for Gettysburg to cut the margin to 11-7 with 4:30 remaining. The Red Devils were also flagged with a one-minute tripping penalty, giving the Bullets a man-up opportunity following the goal.</p>
<p>
	A turnover led to another Gettysburg goal, cutting the lead to 11-8, with 3:45 to play in regulation. The Devils spread the defense and Cherry found a lane to add some insurance with an unassisted tally at the 2:45 mark.</p>
<p>
	Maddox kept the Bullets in it, answering just 21 seconds later to make the score 12-9. Jameson Smith cut the deficit to just a pair, scoring on a feed with 1:41 on the clock.</p>
<p>
	The Devils forced a turnover after Gettysburg won the face-off, drawing a slash penalty with 54 seconds to play to earn a man-up advantage for remainder of regulation. The Bullets were able to gain possession, forcing a turnover with more than 30 seconds left, but the Red Devils held on for the 12-10 win.</p>
<p>
	Gleason recorded a hat trick with three goals on the day. Palladino caused four turnovers, controlled a pair of ground balls and handed out two assists with the long pole. Cannon added two goals and an assist while Cherry and Leon each found the net twice.</p>
<p>
	Senior goaltender Greg Hanley made 10 saves and picked up three ground balls. Moore won 12 face-offs, controlled four ground balls and scored his first goal of the season.</p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/lacrosse-men/article/2013-04-10/no-2-dickinson-holds-comback-gettysburg-12-10-victory</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-mens/lacrosse-men">lacrosse-men</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d3">d3</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/dickinson-college">Dickinson College</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/gettysburg-college">Gettysburg College</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 23:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>gmcmillen</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">173115 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Griffins' five goals power Trinity (Conn.) to lopsided win versus Springfield]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="inline-left photo">
	<img src="/sites/default/files/images/griffin-w-lax-41013.jpg" style="width: 100px; height: 150px;" />
	<div class="photo-caption">
		Griffin</div>
</div>
<p>
	<strong>HARTFORD, Conn.</strong> -- Midfielder Martha Griffin scored a game-high five goals to lead Trinity (Conn.) to a 19-5 victory against visiting Springfield at Sheppard Field. Reigning NCAA champion Trinity, ranked No. 1 in the nation, tied a program-record 18 wins in a row set in 2011, while improving to 10-0. Springfield fell to 7-6.</p>
<p>
	Trinity controlled play from the beginning, opening up a 6-0 led after 19:22 of play. Bantam senior attacker Hadley Duncan scored the game&#39;s first goal from senior attacker Haley Thompson 1:53 after the opening draw, and senior midfielder Megan Leonhard tallied three goals to highlight a 6-0 Trinity run to started the game.</p>
<p>
	Freshman midfielder Connie Nielson ended the Springfield scoring drought with back-to-back scores at 15:45 and 13:02 of the first half, respectively. Sophomore midfielder Michelle Dorsey scored the third consecutive Pride goal 28 seconds later to make the score 6-3.</p>
<p>
	The Bantams closed the first half with a 5-0 run that included consecutive goals by Griffin in the final three minutes before the break. After a goal by Dorsey from Nielson 30 second after halftime, junior attacker Shea Kusiak scored on a free position for the Bantams to ignite a 5-0 run that put the game out of reach. Attacker Molly Cox scored twice during the spurt.</p>
<p>
	Trinity sophomore midfielder Lindsay Mullaney was the fifth of five Bantam multiple-goal scorers with two, while Thompson and junior attacker Kathleen Timmons dished two assists apiece, and Leonhard had a game-high four draw controls and forced three turnovers. The Bantam defense of senior Mallory Hinman, senior Hillary McNamara, and juniors Midge Daniel and Lyndsey Shepard held Springfield to just eight shots and caused 11 turnovers, as Emily Mooney and senior Olivia Whitney did not make a save in 60 minutes in the Bantam goal. Junior backstop Anne Versprille had 11 stops for Springfield.</p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/lacrosse-women/article/2013-04-10/griffins-five-goals-power-trinity-conn-lopsided-win-versus-sp</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-womens/lacrosse-women">lacrosse-women</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d3">d3</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/springfield-college">Springfield College</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/trinity-college-connecticut">Trinity College (Connecticut)</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 23:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>smoussawel</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">173111 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[What they're facing]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>
	<strong>CANTON, Mich. --</strong> This will not be easy.</p>
<p>
	Coaches -- and thereby competitors, were given a look Wednesday at the lane graph for the national championship tournament, which will get under way Thursday morning at Super Bowl Lanes.</p>
<p>
	Think of the lane graph like a course book in golf. It gives the competitors a look at the hazards they&#39;ll face. Unlike golf however, those hazards aren&#39;t visible to the naked eye.</p>
<p>
	The lanes are dressed with oil -- sometimes called lane conditioner. When the ball hits the oil, it acts like a car tire trying to gain traction on ice. The more oil the ball comes in contact with, the more the ball will skid, or go straight. When the ball hits a dry area, it creates friction and the ball will hook -- or curve -- in the same direction as the rotation of the ball (usually left to right for lefties and from right to left for righties).</p>
<p>
	Ideally, competitors are looking for heavier oil in the front part of the lane and less in the back so the ball will save its energy to the end of the shot, therefore hitting the pins harder when it reaches them.</p>
<p>
	The oil pattern this week is 42 feet long -- that&#39;s a few feet longer than your normal &quot;house shot&quot; pattern -- with heavy oil across the lane in the first 10 feet and oil across the lane with the exception of just the first board on each side of the lane. There is more oil in the center of the lane, which give the players a bit of forgivness, but it&#39;s nowhere near the ratio of a common house condition.</p>
<p>
	In short, the players will have to be accurate and will have to be able to repeat shots -- under pressure -- in order to be successful.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/lanesheet.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 830px;" /></p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/bowling/article/2013-04-10/what-theyre-facing</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-womens/bowling">bowling</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d1">d1</category>
 <category domain="/category/auto-created-vocabulary-2/ncaa">NCAA</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 19:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>mspoor</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">173095 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[2013 Division II Softball Conference Championship Central]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<table class="champtable" style="width: 640px;">
	<caption>
		2013 DIVISION II SOFTBALL CONFERENCE CHAMPIONSHIPS</caption>
	<thead>
		<tr>
			<th scope="col">
				Conference</th>
			<th scope="col">
				Date</th>
			<th scope="col">
				*Location</th>
			<th scope="col">
				Venue</th>
			<th scope="col">
				Champion</th>
		</tr>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/ccaa_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.goccaa.org/" target="_blank">California Collegiate Athletic</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				May 3-5</td>
			<td>
				Stockton, Calif.</td>
			<td>
				Arnaiz Stadium</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/cacc_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.caccathletics.org" target="_blank">Central Atlantic Collegiate</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				May 2-4</td>
			<td>
				Lakewood, N.J.</td>
			<td>
				Georgian Court</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/ciaa_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://theciaa.com/landing/index.html" target="_blank">Central Intercollegiate Athletic</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				April 18-20</td>
			<td>
				TBD</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/conference_carolinas_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.conferencecarolinas.com/landing/index" target="_blank">Conference Carolinas</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				April 19-21</td>
			<td>
				Burlington, N.C.</td>
			<td>
				Springwood Park</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/east-coast_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.eccsports.org" target="_blank">East Coast</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				May 2-4</td>
			<td>
				TBD</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/great-american_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.greatamericanconference.com/" target="_blank">Great American</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				April 25-27</td>
			<td>
				Bentonville, Ark.</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/gliac_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.gliac.org/landing/index" target="_blank">Great Lakes Intercoll. Athletic</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				May 3-5</td>
			<td>
				Findlay, Ohio</td>
			<td>
				Marathon Diamonds</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/glvc_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.glvcsports.com/" target="_blank">Great Lakes Valley</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				May 3-5</td>
			<td>
				East Peoria, Ill.</td>
			<td>
				EastSide Centre</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/gnac_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.gnacsports.com/" target="_blank">Great Northwest Athletic</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				May 2-4</td>
			<td>
				Billings, Mont.</td>
			<td>
				Cenex Stadium</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/gulf-south_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.gscsports.org/" target="_blank">Gulf South</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				May 3-5</td>
			<td>
				Southaven, Miss.</td>
			<td>
				Greenbrook Park</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/heartland_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.heartlandsports.org/" target="_blank">Heartland</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				May 2-4</td>
			<td>
				TBD</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/lonestar_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.lonestarconference.org" target="_blank">Lone Star</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				May 3-5</td>
			<td>
				Canyon, Texas</td>
			<td>
				Schaeffer Park</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/miaa-d2_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.themiaa.com/landing/index" target="_blank">Mid-America Intercoll. Athletics</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				May 2-5</td>
			<td>
				Overland Park, Kan.</td>
			<td>
				Blue Valley Recreation Complex</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/northeast10_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.northeast10.org/landing/index" target="_blank">Northeast-10</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				April 30, May 2-4</td>
			<td>
				TBD</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/nsic_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.northernsun.org/" target="_blank">Northern Sun Intercollegiate</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				May 2-4</td>
			<td>
				Rochester, Minn.</td>
			<td>
				Rochester Comm. College</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/pacific-west_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.thepacwest.com/landing/index" target="_blank">Pacific West</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				None</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/peach-belt_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.peachbeltconference.org/landing/index" target="_blank">Peach Belt</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				April 20-21</td>
			<td>
				St. Augustine, Fla.</td>
			<td>
				Flagler Field</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/psac_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.psacsports.org/" target="_blank">Pennsylvania State Athletic</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				May 1-4</td>
			<td>
				Quakertown, Pa.</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/rmac_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.rmacsports.org/landing/index" target="_blank">Rocky Mountain Athletic</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				May 2-4</td>
			<td>
				TBD</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/sac_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.thesac.com/" target="_blank">South Atlantic</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				April 18-21</td>
			<td>
				Salisbury, N.C.</td>
			<td>
				Whitley Softball Field</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/siac_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.thesiac.com/index.aspx?skip=true" target="_blank">Southern Intercollegiate Athletic</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				April 18-20</td>
			<td>
				Hampton, Ga.</td>
			<td>
				Mathews Sports Complex</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/sunshine-state_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.sunshinestateconference.com/" target="_blank">Sunshine State</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				None</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td class="rtecenter">
				<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/logos/Small%20Conferences/wviac_40.png" style="width: 40px; height: 40px;" /><br />
				<span style="font-size:11px;"><strong><a href="http://www.wviac.org/" target="_blank">West Virginia Intercoll. Athletic</a></strong></span></td>
			<td>
				May 2-4</td>
			<td>
				Vienna, W. Va.</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
			<td>
				&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td colspan="5">
				*Final site location only</td>
		</tr>
	</tbody>
</table>
<p>
	&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/softball/article/2013-04-10/2013-division-ii-softball-conference-championship-central</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-womens/softball">softball</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d2">d2</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 19:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>dkroll</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">173091 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Act like they've been there before]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>
	When you take a look at the list of teams vying for the 2013 NC Bowling Championship beginning Thursday at Super Bowl Lanes in Canton, Mich., two-time defending national champion Maryland-Eastern Shore is sure to grab your attention.</p>
<p>
	And it should. After all, the Hawks are two-time defending national champions and have won 10 tournaments this season. What&#39;s more, they haven&#39;t finished worse than second in any event they&#39;ve competed in this year.</p>
<p>
	&quot;We are honored to be the second overall selection,&quot; head coach Kristina Frahm said. &quot;I do feel, however that we have a top team and I think our experiences can help us make a serious run at winning another national championship.</p>
<p>
	<table class="inline-left" style="width: 250px;">
	<thead>
		<tr>
			<th scope="col">
				2013 NC BOWLING CHAMPIONSHIP</th>
		</tr>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<strong>Preview</strong></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Spoor: <a href="/news/bowling/article/2013-04-03/act-theyve-been-there">No shortage of experience in field</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				What They&#39;re Facing: <a href="/news/bowling/article/2013-04-10/what-theyre-facing">The lane conditions</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				&bull; <a href="/news/bowling/article/2013-03-27/eight-team-field-selected-national-championship-tournament">Championship participants chosen</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<a class="video-blue" href="http://ncaasite.turner.com/video/bowling/2013-03-27/nc-womens-bowling-2013-selection-show" rel="article">Watch the selection show</a></td>
		</tr>
	</tbody>
</table></p>
<p>
	&quot;Obviously, we are looking for a three-peat.&quot;</p>
<p>
	Look a bit further at the team list and you&#39;ll notice that the field includes every school that has won the national championship since its inception in 2004.</p>
<p>
	Current NTCA No. 1 Nebraska won the first two championships in 2004 and &#39;05 and the Huskers hoisted the hardware again in 2009. The Huskers, like the Hawks, have participated in every national championship tournament. This season&#39;s Huskers, however, sport a bit of a different look than in years past. The team boasts just one senior, team leader Kristina Mickelson, who suffered a cracked elbow in a car accident in September and has seen limited action this season.</p>
<p>
	&quot;She&#39;s pretty gritty,&quot; head coach Bill Straub said. &quot;She&#39;s been wearing herself out with applications of Icy-Hot. She&#39;s had a restrictor on her elbow to kind of keep things tight so it&#39;s not too troublesome for her, but she just grits her teeth and plays along.</p>
<p>
	&quot;It&#39;s been a tough year for her, but not through lack of effort.&quot;</p>
<p>
	Mickelson&#39;s roommate, sophomore Liz Kuhlkin, has been more than a pleasant surprise this season, Straub said. She&#39;s earned spots on four different All-Tournament teams this season.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	&quot;Surprised might be too strong, but certainly well-pleased,&quot; Straub said of Kulikin. &quot;She&#39;s worked her tail off to try to help us out as best she can and she&#39;s just continuing to develop as a player and she&#39;s turned into quite an excellent one.&quot;</p>
<p>
	Central Missouri is ranked No. 2 in the country and enters the tournament as the No. 1 seed after snagging three tournament titles. The Jennies are led by senior Natalie Jimenez, who has averaged 209.60 this season while garnering a pair of Most Outstanding Player honors, including one at the McKendree Duals where she averaged more than 239.</p>
<p>
	Vanderbilt lost to UMES in the championship game in 2011. Last year in Cleveland, the Commodores lost to Fairleigh Dickinson in the last semifinal match. This year, Vandy will make its eighth trip to the championship tournament.</p>
<p>
	Head coach John Williamson says while it may seem differently, his team&#39;s consistency has not come easily.</p>
<p>
	&quot;Because we have had a nice run of success, it might be tempting for some fans to think this is easily attained but anyone closely following the regular season can attest that there are more quality teams than ever before and some very good teams were not chosen.&quot;</p>
<p>
	Just as Nebraska, the Commodores come to the championship with just one senior starter --&nbsp; Jessica Earnest, a three-time All-American who averaged 207 in team games and 212 in Baker contests.</p>
<p>
	Expect Vanderbilt to rely heavily on its underclassmen, including freshman Robyn Renslow, who often bowled in the anchor spot thanks to her 208.5 average Another freshman, lefty Amanda Fry, averaged 210 was the Most Outstanding Player at the Sam Houston State Track Kat Klash.</p>
<p>
	Fairleigh Dickinson, which lost to UMES in last year&#39;s final and won titles in 2006 and &#39;10, is back again as the eighth and final seed.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;I am so proud of this team,&rdquo; head coach Mike LoPresti said. &ldquo;Now we have a new life and a second season. We went through a lot of transitions this year with a combination of a few veterans and a lot of new players. We&#39;re so happy to extend the season because we have made so many improvements, and now we get to put it all together on the nation&#39;s biggest stage.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	One of those key veterans for the Knights is senior Danielle McEwen, last year&#39;s NTCA Division I Bowler of the Year. McEwen appears poised for more honors in Detroit. She averages 216.52 with a strike percentage of 54.65. In January, earned the individual championship at the USBC Team USA Trials for the second consecutive year. As a result, McEwan will be the sole US representative at the QubicaAMF World Cup and will be a member of Team USA during the calendar year.</p>
<p>
	For right now, however, McEwen is focused on enjoying this week.</p>
<p>
	&quot;It&#39;s not enough for me just to make it, especially in my senior year,&quot; she said. I want to... go into nationals with a different mindset and hopefully come out with a better outcome.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	As for those defending champion Hawks, they are led by Colombian left-hander Anggie Ramirez. Recently named a finalist for the International Bowling Media Association College Bowler of the Year, Ramirez averaged nearly 213 during the regular season and earned MEAC Bowler of the Year, All-MEAC First-Team, MEAC Championship MVP and MEAC All-Tournament Team awards. She was also named the conference&#39;s Bowler of the Week six times.</p>
<p>
	&quot;It was always my dream since I was MEAC Rookie of the Year to be MEAC Player of the Year. Now that I won this and MVP of the tournament, I am so happy that my dream could come true,&quot; Ramirez said.</p>
<p>
	Competition begins with qualifying rounds on Thursday, April 11, in which each team bowls one five-person regular team game against each of the other seven teams participating in the championship for a total of seven games.</p>
<p>
	Bracket play begins Friday morning, as teams will be seeded based on Thursday&rsquo;s record during team qualifying. Teams will then compete in best-of-seven-games Baker matches in a double-elimination tournament.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	In the Baker format, each of the five team members, in order, bowls a complete frame until a complete (10-frame) game is bowled.&nbsp; A Baker match tied 3&frac12; games to 3&frac12; games after seven games will be decided by a tiebreaker using the Modified Baker format.</p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/bowling/article/2013-04-10/act-theyve-been-there</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-womens/bowling">bowling</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d1">d1</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 19:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>mspoor</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">171327 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[ASA/USA Softball announces top 25 finalists for 2013 Player of the Year]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>
	<strong>OKLAHOMA CITY, Okla.</strong> -- The Amateur Softball Association (ASA) of America and USA Softball announced the top 25 finalists for the 2013 USA Softball Collegiate Player of the Year, which will be announced at the opening of the 2013 NCAA Women&rsquo;s College World Series (WCWS) in Oklahoma City. This award, which is considered the most prestigious honor in Division I women&rsquo;s collegiate softball, is designed to recognize the outstanding athletic achievement by female players across the country.</p>
<p>
	Now in its 12th year, previous recipients of the USA Softball Collegiate Player of the Year award are UCLA catcher Stacey Nuveman (2002), Texas pitcher Cat Osterman (2003, 2005 and 2006), Florida State pitcher Jessica Van der Linden (2004), Tennessee pitcher Monica Abbott (2007), Virginia Tech pitcher Angela Tincher (2008), Washington pitcher Danielle Lawrie (2009 and 2010), Stanford shortstop Ashley Hansen (2011), and Oklahoma pitcher Keilani Ricketts (2012), who is also among the list of top 25 finalists this season.</p>
<p>
	This year&rsquo;s list is comprised of 11 seniors, eight juniors, four sophomores and two freshmen. The student-athletes selected represent 17 NCAA DI universities and five athletic conferences. Alabama leads the way among universities with four athlete representatives, followed by Oklahoma and Tennessee with three apiece, Texas with two and Arizona State, Arkansas, California, Florida, Louisville, LSU, Michigan, Missouri, Notre Dame, Oregon, Penn State, South Florida and Washington each have one member.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	Just prior to the start of post-season play, on May 8, the list will be narrowed to the top 10 finalists. The top three will be announced May 22, while the winner of the 2013 USA Softball Collegiate Player of the Year award will be revealed on May 28.</p>
<p>
	The USA Softball Collegiate Player of the Year award is voted on by coaching representatives from 11 DI Conferences in the 15 ASA Regions, as well as members of the media who consistently cover DI Softball across the country.</p>
<p>
	In addition to bestowing the USA Softball Collegiate Player of the Year award, ASA/USA Softball is now in its 11th season of presenting the ESPN.com/USA Softball Collegiate Top 25 Poll and the USA Softball Collegiate Player of the Week, which are announced Tuesdays during the regular season.</p>
<table class="inline-left" style="width: 640px;">
	<thead>
		<tr>
			<th scope="col">
				Name</th>
			<th scope="col">
				School</th>
			<th scope="col">
				Class</th>
			<th scope="col">
				Position</th>
			<th scope="col">
				Hometown</th>
		</tr>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Cassidy Bell</td>
			<td>
				Penn State</td>
			<td>
				Senior</td>
			<td>
				Outfield</td>
			<td>
				Bakersfield, Calif.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Kayla Braud</td>
			<td>
				Alabama</td>
			<td>
				Senior</td>
			<td>
				Outfield</td>
			<td>
				Eugene, Ore.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Lauren Chamberlain</td>
			<td>
				Oklahoma</td>
			<td>
				Sophomore</td>
			<td>
				Infield</td>
			<td>
				Trabuco Canyon, Calif.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Raven Chavanne</td>
			<td>
				Tennessee</td>
			<td>
				Senior</td>
			<td>
				Third Base/Outfield</td>
			<td>
				Thousand Oaks, Calif.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Rachele Fico</td>
			<td>
				LSU</td>
			<td>
				Senior</td>
			<td>
				Pitcher</td>
			<td>
				Oxford, Conn.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Amber Freeman</td>
			<td>
				Arizona State</td>
			<td>
				Sophomore</td>
			<td>
				Catcher</td>
			<td>
				Lakewood, Calif.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Michelle Gascoigne</td>
			<td>
				Oklahoma</td>
			<td>
				Senior</td>
			<td>
				Pitcher</td>
			<td>
				Benicia, Calif.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Lauren Gibson</td>
			<td>
				Tennessee</td>
			<td>
				Senior</td>
			<td>
				Second Base</td>
			<td>
				Pasadena, Md.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Jolene Henderson</td>
			<td>
				California</td>
			<td>
				Senio</td>
			<td>
				Pitcher/First Base</td>
			<td>
				Elk Grove, Calif.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Taylor Hoagland</td>
			<td>
				Texas</td>
			<td>
				Senior</td>
			<td>
				Outfield/Infield</td>
			<td>
				Flower Mound, Texas</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Kaila Hunt</td>
			<td>
				Alabama</td>
			<td>
				Junior</td>
			<td>
				Infield</td>
			<td>
				Evans, Ga.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Kaitlin Inglesby</td>
			<td>
				Washington</td>
			<td>
				Junior</td>
			<td>
				Pitcher/First Base</td>
			<td>
				Portland, Ore.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Katie Keller</td>
			<td>
				Louisville</td>
			<td>
				Junior</td>
			<td>
				Second Base</td>
			<td>
				Livermore, Calif.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Emilee Koerner</td>
			<td>
				Notre Dame</td>
			<td>
				Sophomore</td>
			<td>
				Outfield</td>
			<td>
				Tustin, Calif.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Blaire Luna</td>
			<td>
				Texas</td>
			<td>
				Senior</td>
			<td>
				Pitcher</td>
			<td>
				Austin, Texas</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Haylie McCleney</td>
			<td>
				Alabama</td>
			<td>
				Freshman</td>
			<td>
				Outfield</td>
			<td>
				Morris, Ala.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Jessica Moore</td>
			<td>
				Oregon</td>
			<td>
				Senior</td>
			<td>
				Pitcher</td>
			<td>
				Sutter, Calif.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Sara Nevins</td>
			<td>
				South Florida</td>
			<td>
				Junior</td>
			<td>
				Pitcher</td>
			<td>
				Pinellas Park, Fla.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Ellen Renfroe</td>
			<td>
				Tennessee</td>
			<td>
				Junior</td>
			<td>
				Pitcher</td>
			<td>
				Jackson, Tenn.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Keilani Ricketts</td>
			<td>
				Oklahoma</td>
			<td>
				Senior</td>
			<td>
				Pitcher</td>
			<td>
				San Jose, Calif.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Hannah Rogers</td>
			<td>
				Florida</td>
			<td>
				Junior</td>
			<td>
				Pitcher</td>
			<td>
				Lake Wales, Fla.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Sierra Romero</td>
			<td>
				Michigan</td>
			<td>
				Freshman</td>
			<td>
				Infield</td>
			<td>
				Murrieta, Calif.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Chelsea Thomas</td>
			<td>
				Missouri</td>
			<td>
				Senior</td>
			<td>
				Pitcher</td>
			<td>
				Pleasantville, Iowa</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Jackie Traina</td>
			<td>
				Alabama</td>
			<td>
				Junior</td>
			<td>
				Pitcher/Designated player</td>
			<td>
				Naples, Fla.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Devon Wallace</td>
			<td>
				Arkansas</td>
			<td>
				Sophomore</td>
			<td>
				Utility</td>
			<td>
				Double Oak, Texas</td>
		</tr>
	</tbody>
</table>
<p>
	<br />
	&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/softball/article/2013-04-10/asausa-softball-announces-top-25-finalists-2013-player-year</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-womens/softball">softball</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d1">d1</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 18:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>smoussawel</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">173075 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Hofstra hires Niagara's Mihalich as 12th head coach in program history]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="inline-left photo">
	<img src="/sites/default/files/images/Hofstra-Newcoach-mug.jpg" style="width: 100px; height: 150px;" />
	<div class="photo-caption">
		Mihalich</div>
</div>
<p>
	<strong>HEMPSTEAD, N.Y. --</strong> Joe Mihalich is leaving behind 15 successful seasons at Niagara to take over Hofstra&#39;s men&#39;s basketball program.</p>
<p>
	The 56-year-old was announced by the school as its 12th basketball coach on Wednesday.</p>
<p>
	Several media outlets, including Newsday and The Buffalo News, reported Mihalich&#39;s hiring Tuesday night.</p>
<p>
	Mihalich replaces Mo Cassara, who was fired March 22 following a 7-25 season. Four Pride players were arrested in November on burglary charges stemming from dormitory room break-ins.</p>
<p>
	Hofstra lands an established coach and respected recruiter in Mihalich, who played a big role in reviving the Purple Eagles&#39; proud basketball tradition. He finished his tenure at Niagara with a 265-203 record and five postseason berths, including two NCAA tournament appearances in 2005 and &#39;07.</p>
<p>
	Before Mihalich, the Purple Eagles had reached the NCAA tournament only once, in 1970, when the team was led by Calvin Murphy and coached by Frank Layden.</p>
<p>
	Niagara also earned three NIT berths, including this year, when the Purple Eagles (19-14) won their third Metro Atlantic Athletic Conference regular-season championship under Mihalich.</p>
<p>
	He&#39;s a three-time MAAC coach of the year, and won 20 or more games four times while experiencing only three losing seasons at Niagara.</p>
<p>
	Last week, he was selected the Skip Prosser Man of the Year, which has been award annually since 2008 to honor the nation&#39;s Division I men&#39;s basketball coach who exhibits strong moral character.</p>
<p>
	At Hofstra, he takes over a Colonial Athletic Association program that has stumbled on and off the court over the past two seasons. The Pride have gone 17-47 in their past two years after a 21-12 finish in Cassara&#39;s first season in 2010-11.</p>
<p>
	Hofstra hasn&#39;t reached the NCAA tournament since consecutive appearances in 2000 and &#39;01. The Pride also earned three consecutive NIT berths from 2005-07.</p>
<p>
	The Pride&#39;s season didn&#39;t get off to a good start last year after Taran Buie and Jamal Coombs-McDaniel were suspended by Cassara for two preseason events and two regular-season games for violating team rules.</p>
<p>
	In late November, sophomore Shaquille Stokes and freshmen Kentrell Washington, Jimmy Hall and Dallas Anglin were charged in six burglaries that occurred Oct. 4-5.</p>
<p>
	<strong>Related:</strong><br />
	&bull; <a href="/news/basketball-men/article/2013-03-19/2013-mens-hoops-coaching-carousel">Coaching Carousel</a><br />
	&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/basketball-men/article/2013-04-10/hofstra-hires-niagaras-mihalich-12th-head-coach-program-histo</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-mens/basketball-men">basketball-men</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d1">d1</category>
 <category domain="/category/auto-created-vocabulary-2/ap">AP</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/hofstra-university">Hofstra University</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/niagara-university">Niagara University</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 16:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>dkroll</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">173067 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Auriemma, UConn blast into record book]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<div id="playerarea-173023">
	&nbsp;</div>
<script language="JavaScript" type="text/javascript">makeVideoPlayer(173023)</script>
<p>
	<strong>NEW ORLEANS</strong> -- Connecticut and Geno Auriemma collected their eighth NCAA Championship trophy on Tuesday night after dominating Louisville, 93-60.</p>
<p>
	With the victory, Connecticut (35-4) maintained its flawless record in national championship games, while Auriemma tied former Tennessee head coach Pat Summitt for most titles.</p>
<p>
	<table class="inline-left" style="width: 250px;">
	<thead>
		<tr>
			<th scope="col">
				2013 WOMEN&#39;S FINAL FOUR</th>
		</tr>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<strong>NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIP<br />
				UConn 93, Louisville 60</strong></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Farnum: <a href="/news/basketball-women/article/2013-04-10/auriemma-uconn-blast-record-book">Auriemma equals Summitt&#39;s eight titles</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				McKesson: <a href="/news/basketball-women/article/2013-04-10/despite-loss-future-bright-cards">Future very bright for Louisville</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<a href="http://www.ncaa.com/game/basketball-women/d1/2013/04/09/louisville-connecticut">Recap</a> | <a class="photos-blue" href="http://galleries.ncaa.com/gallery/2013_Women%27s_Basketball_National_Championship_Game" rel="article" target="_blank">Gallery</a> | <a class="video-blue" href="http://www.ncaa.com/video#!basketball-women/2013-04-09/wbb-601-louisville-uconn-huskies-win-national-championship" rel="video">Highlights</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Head2Head: <a href="http://www.ncaa.com/news/basketball-women/article/2013-04-09/why-theyll-win-louisville-vs-uconn">Why They&#39;ll Win</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Farnum: <a href="http://www.ncaa.com/news/basketball-women/article/2013-04-08/better-sum-parts">Faris puts UConn in &#39;position to win&#39;</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				McKesson: <a href="http://www.ncaa.com/news/basketball-women/article/2013-04-08/these-girls-just-want-have-fun">UofL&#39;s fun approach nothing new</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<strong>SEMIFINALS<br />
				Connecticut 83, Notre Dame 65</strong></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Farnum: <a href="http://www.ncaa.com/news/basketball-women/article/2013-04-08/uconns-next-star-steps-fore">UConn&#39;s next star steps to the fore</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<a href="http://www.ncaa.com/game/basketball-women/d1/2013/04/07/connecticut-notre-dame">Recap</a> | <a class="photos-blue" href="http://galleries.ncaa.com/gallery/2013_Women%27s_Final_Four" rel="article">Gallery</a> | <a class="video-blue" href="http://www.ncaa.com/video/basketball-women/2013-04-07/final-four-uconn-dances-past-irish" rel="article">Highlights</a> | <a class="stats-blue" href="http://www.ncaa.com/game/basketball-women/d1/2013/04/07/connecticut-notre-dame#boxscore" rel="article">Box Score</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<strong>SEMIFINALS<br />
				Louisville 64, California 57</strong></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				McKesson: <a href="http://www.ncaa.com/news/basketball-women/article/2013-04-07/slaughter-s-house-possible-title">Slaughter rules for Louisville</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<a href="http://www.ncaa.com/game/basketball-women/d1/2013/04/07/louisville-california">Recap</a> | <a class="photos-blue" href="http://galleries.ncaa.com/gallery/2013_Women%27s_Final_Four" rel="article">Gallery</a> | <a class="video-blue" href="http://www.ncaa.com/video/basketball-women/2013-04-07/final-four-cardinals-keep-dancing-title-game" rel="article">Highlights</a> | <a class="stats-blue" href="http://www.ncaa.com/game/basketball-women/d1/2013/04/07/louisville-california#boxscore" rel="article">Box Score</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<strong>Preview</strong></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Analysis: <a href="/news/basketball-women/article/2013-04-06/view-bench">Duke&#39;s McCallie breaks down semis</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Farnum: <a href="/news/basketball-women/article/2013-04-06/its-notre-dame-uconn-again">It&#39;s Notre Dame-UConn ... again</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				McKesson: <a href="/news/basketball-women/article/2013-04-06/sister-sister">Schimmel chemistry big for Cards</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Pressers: <a class="video-blue" href="http://www.ncaa.com/video/basketball-women/2013-04-06/final-four-notre-dame-preview" rel="article">Irish</a> | <a class="video-blue" href="http://www.ncaa.com/video/basketball-women/2013-04-06/final-four-connecticut-preview" rel="article">UConn</a> | <a class="video-blue" href="http://www.ncaa.com/video/basketball-women/2013-04-06/final-four-louisville-preview" rel="article">L&#39;ville</a> | <a class="video-blue" href="http://www.ncaa.com/video/basketball-women/2013-04-06/final-four-california-preview" rel="article">Cal</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<a class="photos-blue" href="http://galleries.ncaa.com/gallery_console/gallery/1365279716978" rel="article">Practice Day in New Orleans</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<strong>Essentials</strong></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<a class="video-blue" href="http://www.ncaa.com/video" rel="article">Complete tournament highlights</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<a class="video-blue" href="http://www.ncaa.com/video/basketball-women/2013-04-06/answering-big-easy-questions" rel="article">Try your luck at Big Easy questions</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Brackets: <a class="interactive-white" href="http://www.ncaa.com/interactive-bracket/basketball-women/d1" rel="article">Interactive</a> | <a class="pdf-blue" href="http://www.ncaa.com/sites/default/files/external/gametool/brackets/basketball-women_d1_2012.pdf" rel="article">Printable</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<a href="http://www.ncaa.com/womens-final-four#!event_news">Fan Info</a> | <a href="http://www.ncaa.com/mobile#final-four-app">Download the official app</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Shop: <a href="http://www.shopncaasports.com/">Grab some tourney gear</a></td>
		</tr>
	</tbody>
</table></p>
<p>
	The historical significance was not lost on Auriemma.</p>
<p>
	&quot;The fact I tied Pat Summitt&#39;s record - that puts you in a category with the greatest women&#39;s basketball coach who ever lived,&quot; Auriemma said.</p>
<p>
	Summitt, who retired after last season, is the all-time winningest coach in NCAA basketball -- men&#39;s or women&#39;s and won her eighth title in 2008.</p>
<p>
	&quot;The only person I would compare myself to is Pat Summitt &hellip; and to be there in that spot with her means a lot to me,&quot; Auriemma said.</p>
<p>
	In 28 seasons as UConn&#39;s head coach, Auriemma has posted a 91-17 record in NCAA Tournament play, and been in serious contention to win national titles every year since winning his first one in 1995.</p>
<p>
	&quot;I&#39;m really, really proud of that,&quot; Auriemma said. &quot;Because I know how hard it was to do it. And with each year that goes by and teams get knocked out and teams that everybody thinks are national championship teams or programs that should be in the Final Four and are not, with each year that that happens, I feel even better about what we&#39;ve done. Because I know more than anybody else, and so does my staff, just how incredibly difficult it is to do what we&#39;ve done.&quot;</p>
<p>
	Auriemma holds the record for most consecutive Women&#39;s Final Four appearances with six and has the best NCAA winning percentage of any coach in history (.842).</p>
<p>
	But even Auriemma never dreamt his program could win eight championships.</p>
<p>
	&quot;When we started and got to our first Final Four - here in New Orleans - we almost acted like we didn&#39;t belong,&quot; Auriemma said. &quot;The other three teams were Stanford, Virginia and Tennessee. When we didn&#39;t win, we thought, &#39;what if we never go back? What if we&#39;re one and done?&#39; There are other teams that have made it to the Final Four and never been back.</p>
<p>
	&quot;Then, when we won our first national championship in 1995, I thought lots of people have won one. What if we don&#39;t ever win again? I&#39;m always looking into the future and thinking, &#39;is this it? Are we going to be one of those programs? To back now and see how far we&#39;ve come in the last 18 years, never in our wildest dreams did we think it was possible.&quot;</p>
<p>
	This season, with three losses to Notre Dame and another to Baylor, the Huskies were having a &quot;sub-par&quot; season for the program. After UConn lost against the Irish in the Big East Championship Game, he sat with the team in the locker room and told them he was going to show them how to win a national championship. And, he did.</p>
<p>
	&quot;Sure enough, we&#39;re sitting right here,&quot; senior guard Kelly Faris said. &quot;There are times I don&#39;t know how he does what he does but he&#39;s pretty darn good at his good and figures out a way to get it done. I&#39;m happy to have him on my side.&quot;</p>
<p>
	Incredibly, the Huskies are 8-0 in NCAA title games -- a feat no other program had accomplished.</p>
<p>
	&quot;Eight for eight?&quot; Auriemma said. &quot;Man, oh, man &hellip; I&#39;ve been in the Final Four a couple times when we&#39;ve lost where mentally we weren&#39;t right. But we&#39;ve never been in a championship game where mentally we weren&#39;t right. All eight times that we&#39;ve won a national championship, I felt like my team was mentally ready to win a championship. And I think that&#39;s something that I&#39;m really proud of; that we don&#39;t show up in championship games not ready to play mentally or physically.&quot;</p>
<p>
	<strong>Taking notes</strong></p>
<p>
	<strong>&bull; </strong>The 33-point margin of victory was the largest in a championship game, obliterating the previous mark of 23 points by Tennessee&rsquo;s 1987 championship squad against Louisiana Tech (67-44.)</p>
<p>
	&bull; UConn&rsquo;s win against Louisville marks just the second time that a team has defeated two teams from its conference in the Final Four to claim the national title (Maryland, 2006.)</p>
<p>
	&bull; Breanna Stewart became just the fourth freshman and first since 1987 to be named Most Outstanding Player of the Women&rsquo;s Final Four. The other three were Cheryl Miller (USC, 1983); Clarissa Davis (Texas, 1986); and Tonya Edwards (Tennessee, 1987). Stewart becomes the first freshman since Maryland&rsquo;s Kristi Toliver in 2006, to be made to the Women&rsquo;s Final Four all-tournament team.</p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/basketball-women/article/2013-04-10/auriemma-uconn-blast-record-book</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-womens/basketball-women">basketball-women</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d1">d1</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 06:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>cthomas</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">173039 at </guid>
  </item>  </channel>
</rss>
