<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ncaa.com/newsrss" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>www.ncaa.com</title>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/newsrss</link>
    <description>All Sports</description>
    <category>all</category>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://ncaa.com/newsrss" rel="self"></atom:link>
        
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Top-ranked Amherst eases past No. 28 Bates in conference matchup]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>
	<strong><img alt="" src="http://i.turner.ncaa.com/dr/ncaa/ncaa/release/sites/default/files/images/logos/schools/a/amherst.70.png" style="width: 70px; height: 70px; float: left; margin-left: 3px; margin-right: 3px;" />AMHERST, Mass. --</strong> Top-ranked Amherst remained unbeaten against Division III opponents on Wednesday, cruising to an 8-1 home win against No. 28 Bates. Improving to 6-0 in NESCAC play (13-1 overall), the Jeffs swept doubles play and clinched the match win with four straight-set triumphs in singles.</p>
<p>
	Amherst had little trouble with the Bobcats (5-8, 1-3 NESCAC) at second and third doubles as No. 2 duo Caroline Richman and Safi Aly powered past Bates&rsquo; Nicole Russell and Kristen Doerer 8-2 before Sarah Monteagudo and Isabel Camacho finished off Jacquelyn Holmes and Jenna Burke 8-3. The Bobcats&rsquo; top pair of Elena Mandzhukova and Ashley Brunk provided a stronger challenge to juniors Gabby Devlin and Zoe Pangalos, but the Jeffs were too strong, completing the sweep with an 8-5 win.</p>
<p>
	Amherst sealed the match victory quickly in singles play as Monteagudo breezed past Brunk 6-1, 6-1 at No. 3 and Lauren Slutsky downed Audrey Grauer in the fives contest 6-3, 6-0. Lara Min kept the shutout going with a 6-2, 6-4 win against Doerer at No. 6 while Camacho stopped Russell 6-4, 6-3 at fourth singles.</p>
<p>
	In the two matches to reach a tiebreaker, Richman stepped into the No. 1 spot and held off Mandzhukova 6-1, 4-6, 10-6, but Bates picked up its lone point in the day&rsquo;s most dramatic contest as Aly moved up to No. 2 for Amherst, but could not stop a strong comeback from Holmes, falling 4-6, 6-4, 11-9.</p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/tennis-women/article/2013-04-18/top-ranked-amherst-eases-past-no-28-bates-conference-matchup</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-womens/tennis-women">tennis-women</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d3">d3</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/amherst-college">Amherst College</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/bates-college">Bates College</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 19:42:47 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>gmcmillen</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">174351 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[North Texas takes first game of doubleheader against No. 19 Baylor]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="inline-left photo">
	<img src="/sites/default/files/images/wade-north-texas-wsb-41713.jpg" />
	<div class="photo-caption">
		Wade</div>
</div>
<div>
	<p>
		<strong>DENTON, Texas --</strong> Back-to-back homers by Taylor Schoblocher and Bryana Wade led North Texas to a 5-3 win against No. 19 Baylor on Wednesday at Lovelace Stadium. The Bears came back to split the doubleheader with a 2-1 win in the nightcap.</p>
</div>
<p>
	The Mean Green (19-20) snapped a five-game losing streak with the opening win. North Texas defeated a ranked opponent for the first time since defeating Baylor at home during the 2011 season. Baylor (34-11) is 3-1 this season against the Mean Green.</p>
<p>
	Extra-base hits propelled North Texas to a victory in the opening game, but the Baylor pitchers shut down the Mean Green offense in the nightcap. North Texas outhit the Bears 9-6 in the win. Six of the nine hits were for extra bases. Baylor pitcher Courtney Repka allowed just one run off three hits in the second game.</p>
<p>
	Ashley Kirk (9-7) struck out eight batters and walked only one in her complete-game performance. After giving up three runs in the first three innings, she retired 12 of the final 14 batters.</p>
<p>
	Brittany Simmons (6-8) took the loss in the nightcap, despite giving up just one earned run off six hits. The winning run for Baylor was scored off a Mean Green fielding error in the third inning.</p>
<p>
	Back-to-back solo home runs put North Texas ahead in the fourth inning of the opening game 5-3. Schoblocher led off the inning with a long ball to center field. It was her sixth home run of the season. Wade followed with a home run to left field, the second of her career.</p>
<p>
	North Texas tied the game in the third with three runs off four hits. The Mean Green posted four doubles in the inning, including three that knocked in runs. Karly Williams led off the inning with a two-base hit that skipped past the left fielder. Paige Kisling followed her with a similar hit to left that scored the Mean Green&rsquo;s first run. Brooke Foster plated a second run with the third double of the inning, and Dani Hoff tied the game with her team-leading 11th double of the season.</p>
<p>
	Baylor took an early 3-0 lead with two home runs. Sarah Smith hit a two-run long ball in the first inning, and Holly Holl recorded a solo shot in the third.</p>
<p>
	The Bears scored first in the nightcap, but the Mean Green quickly tied the game in the bottom of the first with an RBI single by Schoblocher.</p>
<p>
	Baylor took the lead in the third inning off a Mean Green fielding error. The Bears outhit the Mean Green 6-3 in the second game.</p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/softball/article/2013-04-18/north-texas-takes-first-game-doubleheader-against-no-19-baylor</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-womens/softball">softball</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d1">d1</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/baylor-university">Baylor University</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/university-north-texas">University of North Texas</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 18:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>lfarquhar</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">174283 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Manering, Jordan quiet Indiana's bats as Ball State upsets 19th-ranked Hoosiers]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="inline-left photo">
	<img src="/sites/default/files/images/manering-mbb-41813.jpg" style="width: 100px; height: 150px;" />
	<div class="photo-caption">
		Manering</div>
</div>
<p>
	<strong>BLOOMINGTON, Ind. </strong>-- Behind starter Clay Manering&#39;s six strong inning on the hill, Ball State notched a 5-3 upset against in-state rival and 19th-ranked Indiana on Wednesday.</p>
<p>
	With the victory, the Cardinals improved to 16-17 overall, while the Hoosiers fell to 26-8.</p>
<p>
	Ball State plated home three runs in the top of the third to take a 3-0 lead. Elbert Devarie reached on a fielder&#39;s choice to score Kevin Schlotter, who reached on a single to start the inning. Sean Godfrey&#39;s sacrifice fly scored Devarie and an ensuing error on the play scored Wes Winkle, who had singled.</p>
<p>
	Indiana responded with one run in the third to close the gap to 3-1, but Ball State added a fourth run in the fourth when Sam Tidaback&#39;s double scored Schlotter.</p>
<p>
	The Hoosiers closed the game to 4-3 with a pair of runs in the sixth.</p>
<p>
	Ball State added an insurance run in the top of the ninth to seal the 5-3 win. The Cardinals&#39; final run was a result of a Devarie double, followed by a pair of sacrifice bunts from Winkle and Blake Beemer.</p>
<p>
	Manering allowed two earned runs and struck out four batters to bring his record to 2-2 on the season. Tyler Jordan came on in relief and pitched the final three innings, allowing no hits and striking out one.</p>
<p>
	Devarie was 1-for-4 on the day with an RBI and two runs scored. Godfrey was 1-for-3 with an RBI, while Tidaback was 2-for-3 with and RBI.</p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/baseball/article/2013-04-18/manering-jordan-quiet-indianas-bats-ball-state-upsets-19th-ranked-h</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-mens/baseball">baseball</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d1">d1</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/ball-state-university">Ball State University</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/indiana-university-bloomington">Indiana University, Bloomington</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 18:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>smoussawel</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">174279 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[No. 12 Washington College earns first "War on the Shore" victory since 2002]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="inline-left photo">
	<img src="/sites/default/files/images/finalNowicki.jpg" />
	<div class="photo-caption">
		Nowicki</div>
</div>
<div>
	<p>
		<strong>CHESTERTOWN, Md. --</strong> Junior midfielder Hunter Nowicki scored what would prove to be the game-winning goal with 1:04 remaining to cap off a 4-0 fourth quarter for 12th-ranked Washington College as the Shoremen rallied to beat fifth-ranked Salisbury 7-6 in the annual &quot;War on the Shore&quot; for the Charles B. Clark Cup. The victory was the first in the series for the Shoremen (11-2) since 2002, their first at home against the Sea Gulls (13-4) since 1990 and their first since the cup was added to the series in 2004.</p>
</div>
<p>
	The Sea Gulls appeared to have taken control of the game after outscoring the Shoremen 4-1 in the third quarter to build a 6-3 lead. Washington trimmed the margin to 6-4 just 1:13 into the quarter when sophomore midfielder Luke Birnbaum scored his first goal of the season off an assist from junior attackman JD Campbell. The Shoremen got back to within a goal when sophomore midfielder Grant Hughes scored an unassisted tally with 6:05 to play. Washington did not even the score until an outside shot from junior midfielder Kodie Englehart off an assist from senior attackman Bennett Cord with 2:17 remaining.</p>
<p>
	Sophomore midfielder Michael Trapp won the ensuing face-off for Washington and scooped up a ground ball. Nowicki found the back of the net for the Shoremen after charging down the right side and firing the ball into the back of the net from a dozen yards out. Salisbury was whistled for its third faceoff violation of the half on the next face-off and the Shoremen were able to run out the clock and hold on for the win.</p>
<p>
	The Shoremen started the game strong, outshooting the Sea Gulls 12-3 in the first quarter and taking a 2-1 lead after one period. Cord opened the scoring with 12:21 left in the first before Wade Korvin evened things up with 8:05 to play. Hughes put Washington in front with a goal with 1:32 left.</p>
<p>
	Salisbury held a 12-6 advantage in shots in the second quarter and netted the only score of the period when Greg Korvin found Tyler Smith for a goal with 10:10 to play.</p>
<p>
	The third quarter belonged to Salisbury as the Sea Gulls enjoyed a 14-3 advantage in shots. Salisbury scored on its first two shots of the quarter as Kluge scored just 40 seconds into the period and then found Zach Hill for a goal 34 seconds later. Freshman midfielder David McBrien scored for Washington with 12:28 on the clock to narrow the margin to 4-3, but Hill scored a behind-the-back goal off an assist from John Brewer with 6:48 left and then netted an unassisted goal with 3:06 remaining to build the three-goal cushion.</p>
<p>
	Salisbury finished with a narrow 34-32 advantage in shots in the game after Washington held an 11-5 advantage in the fourth quarter. Trapp took every face-off for Washington and won nine of 16 draws, including the last three. Salisbury committed 20 turnovers in the game - including eighth in the fourth quarter - to Washington&#39;s 17. The Sea Gulls turned the ball over on each of their last six possessions.</p>
<p>
	Hughes was the only Shoreman with multiple goals, netting two on the night, while Cord tallied one goal and one assist. Hill&#39;s three third-quarter goals led all scorers, while Kluge had one goal and one assist for the Sea Gulls.</p>
<p>
	Both goalies turned in strong performances as Washington junior Ted DiSalvo and Salisbury&#39;s Alex Taylor each made 11 saves.</p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/lacrosse-men/article/2013-04-18/no-12-washington-college-earns-first-war-shore-victory-2002</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-mens/lacrosse-men">lacrosse-men</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d3">d3</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/salisbury-university">Salisbury University</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/washington-college-maryland">Washington College (Maryland)</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 17:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>gmcmillen</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">174275 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Primed for first championship]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>
	<strong>LOS ANGELES</strong> -- The routines that Florida employs in competition have been characterized as risky, but so far it has paid off for the Gators.</p>
<p>
	Florida enters the NCAA Women&rsquo;s Gymnastic Championships as the top seed of the 12-team field after an impressive performance in the regionals where it posted a score of 198.40, the nation&rsquo;s second-highest score.</p>
<p>
	The Gators, along with Alabama, Oklahoma, Georgia, LSU, UCLA, Michigan, Minnesota, Stanford, Utah, Arkansas and Illinois, will compete for the title beginning Friday at UCLA&rsquo;s Pauley Pavilion.</p>
<p>
	Rhonda Faehn, Florida&rsquo;s head coach, believes her team is ready to claim its first NCAA championship.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;We really feel like we&#39;re getting to the point of peaking and doing the plan that we were hoping for, and we take it one day at a time and are really trying to enjoy the ride,&rdquo; Faehn said. &ldquo;The field is just so incredibly strong and tough and it&#39;s going to be an incredible championship atmosphere.&quot;</p>
<p>
	<table class="inline-left" style="width: 250px;">
	<thead>
		<tr>
			<th scope="col">
				2013 WOMEN&#39;S GYM CHAMPIONSHIPS</th>
		</tr>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<strong>PREVIEW</strong></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Reger: <a href="/news/gymnastics-women/article/2013-04-18/primed-first-championship">Florida in search of first crown in L.A.</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				&bull; <a href="/news/gymnastics-women/article/2013-04-07/championship-qualifiers-announced">Championship qualifiers announced</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				More: <a href="http://www.ncaa.com/championships/gymnastics-women/d1">Championship Information</a> | <a href="http://www.ncaa.com/history/gymnastics-women/nc">History</a></td>
		</tr>
	</tbody>
</table>Florida knows that being the No. 1 seed is no guarantee of taking home the title. The Gators were the top seed last year and finished second behind Alabama.</p>
<p>
	The Crimson Tide is trying to become only the third team in women&#39;s gymnastics to win three consecutive titles. Georgia won five in a row from 2005 to 2009. Utah did the same from 1982 to 1986.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;The goal for our team each and every year is to have the opportunity to be on the floor at the national championship with a chance to win a championship,&rdquo; Alabama head coach Sarah Patterson said. &ldquo;We know that of the 12 teams, we&#39;ve seen almost all of them and certainly four of the six in our session. So, we just feel like the competition in the last few years has become amazing, and I just feel like on any given night, any one of these teams can advance to the Super Six, and on any given night, any team can win the national championship.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Just becoming one of the 12 teams in the championship can provide enough pressure, especially at Utah, where the team hasn&rsquo;t missed a championship in 38 years.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;It is a burden that our athletes carry that streak, but we were really proud of them to get through regionals, always pressure-packed for all the teams,&rdquo; Utah head coach Megan Marsden said. &ldquo;The young team that we have assembled this year really had to step up when they lost their team captain, Corrie Lothrop, early in the season, and this team has really improved beyond our wildest dreams.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	The parity with the 12 teams is evident in the rankings, where less than a point separates teams two through 10.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;I think because of the tremendous amount of parity throughout the country and the win-losses against teams and the up and downs, the wins up and down, the rankings has made for a really exciting season and create a lot of excitement in our home arena and in our away trips,&rdquo; LSU head coach DD Breaux said. &ldquo;I think that the culmination of the season at UCLA is going to be very exciting for everyone.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	The host school, UCLA, is seeded sixth, but the Bruins have been besieged by injuries most of the year. Peng-Peng Lee and Sam Peszek were lost due to knee injuries and Mattie Larson dislocated her knee in March.</p>
<p>
	UCLA head coach Valorie Kondos-Field is hoping her team can create some upsets.</p>
<p>
	&ldquo;When you lose three of your top athletes for the season, it becomes even more stressful,&rdquo; Kondos-Field said. &ldquo;When you have won championships before, you are expected to do that every single year. But I honestly can say this has been one of, if not the most, enjoyable year for me.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	<em>For the latest updates and tweets from the women&rsquo;s gymnastics championships, please search on Twitter with #ncaawgym.</em></p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/gymnastics-women/article/2013-04-18/primed-first-championship</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-womens/gymnastics-women">gymnastics-women</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d1">d1</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/louisiana-state-university">Louisiana State University</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/university-alabama-tuscaloosa">University of Alabama, Tuscaloosa</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/university-california-los-angeles">University of California, Los Angeles</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/university-florida">University of Florida</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/university-utah">University of Utah</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 16:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>smoussawel</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">174267 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Spring postseason approaches]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>
	The men&rsquo;s lacrosse postseason is approaching with blazing speed and teams are looking for wins anywhere they can get them in order to secure one of those few berths into the NCAA tournament.</p>
<p>
	In other words, it&rsquo;s crunch time.</p>
<p>
	There is probably no better example on the Division I schedule this weekend than the<strong> Villanova-Notre Dame game.</strong></p>
<p>
	After starting the season with a 1-5 record, the Wildcats have won four of their last five games and are 5-6 heading into the weekend. At first glance, a 5-6 record doesn&rsquo;t look like much, but Villanova is 4-0 in Big East Conference action, including a victory against <strong>No. 4 Syracuse</strong>. Each of the Wildcats&rsquo; losses has come at the hands of teams ranked in the top 20 (<strong>Maryland</strong>, <strong>Princeton</strong>, <strong>Lehigh</strong>, <strong>Drexel</strong>, <strong>Penn</strong> and <strong>Penn State</strong>).</p>
<p>
	The Wildcats&rsquo; late-season surge has not gone unnoticed. Villanova cracked the latest USILA and Inside Lacrosse national polls at No. 19 on Monday.</p>
<p>
	This weekend, the Wildcats will certainly be looking to cause a stir when they visit the second-ranked Irish. Notre Dame is 9-2 and 3-1 in league play, and has beaten some of the top teams in the nation -- Duke, North Carolina, Denver, Penn State to name a few -- but the Irish have also been known to let their guard down a little, falling to pesky teams like<strong> Hofstra</strong> and <strong>St. John&rsquo;s (N.Y.)</strong> on their home turf.</p>
<p>
	The Wildcats bring the nation&rsquo;s top man-up offense (.529) into the contest, along with one of the best face-off specialists in the game, <strong>Thomas Croonquist</strong>, who wins 56.3 percent of the time.&nbsp; Croonquist has posted 15 face-off wins in three games this year. Additionally, junior <strong>John LoCascio</strong> is national leader in ground balls per game with 3.9. LoCascio has caused 18 turnovers and grabbed 36 ground balls in the last four contests.</p>
<p>
	Villanova will have their hands full trying to score on Notre Dame&rsquo;s stingy defense. The Irish are giving up just 7.82 goals per game, and boast a man-down defense of .759. Senior goalkeeper <strong>John Kemp </strong>has compiled a 7.65 goals against average on the year.</p>
<p>
	The game will have Big East regular-season title implications as there is just one regular-season contest remaining on the schedule for both squads. The Wildcats have already clinched a berth in the league tournament, but the Irish are still one victory away.</p>
<script language="JavaScript" type="text/javascript">makeVideoPlayer(147183)</script>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/2011/Did_You_Know.jpg" style="width: 630px; height: 50px; float: left;" /></p>
<p>
	&bull; In the 31 years since the NCAA women&rsquo;s gymnastics championships has been in existence, there have only been four programs that have claimed the crown &ndash;<strong> Georgia</strong> (10), <strong>Utah</strong>, (9), <strong>UCLA</strong> (6) and <strong>Alabama</strong> (6). Will this be the year another team breaks through?&nbsp; Both<strong> No. 1 Florida </strong>and <strong>No. 2 Oklahoma</strong> certainly have a shot at winning their first NCAA title, but the four previous winners are also in the running.&nbsp; Beginning Friday, UCLA is hosting the event for the fourth time, and first time in the New Pauley Pavilion, which underwent a $136 million dollar renovation last year.&nbsp; The last time the Bruins hosted the championships was in 2004 when they set a NCAA Super Six record with a winning score of 198.125.</p>
<p>
	&bull; Something will have to give when two of the nation&rsquo;s top scoring defenses collide on Saturday as the<strong> No. 3 Florida</strong> women&rsquo;s lacrosse team hosts American Lacrosse Conference rival and<strong> fourth-ranked</strong> <strong>Northwestern</strong> in a battle for the top spot in the league standings. The Gators are giving up the third-least goals per game (6.88), while the Wildcats are ranked fifth in scoring defense, allowing just 7.29 goals per game. At 3-1 against conference opponents, Florida needs to knock off Northwestern, which is unbeaten in league play, in order to claim a share of the regular-season ALC title. Penn State is also 3-1 in the ALC standings, and will play <strong>Johns Hopkins</strong> on Sunday at noon live on ESPNU.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	&bull;The <strong>No. 12 Yale</strong> men&rsquo;s lacrosse team will look to extend its five-game winning streak in perhaps the Bulldogs&rsquo; most challenging contest of the season when they travel to No. 4 Maryland for a non-conference tilt on Saturday at noon.&nbsp; The Bulldogs&rsquo; three losses this season have come by a combined margin of four goals, including a 12-10 setback to then-No. 2 <strong>Cornell</strong> on March 16.&nbsp; In addition, two victories during Yale&rsquo;s five-game winning streak have been in overtime, including an 11-10 defeat of<strong> Stony Brook </strong>on Monday.</p>
<p>
	&bull; The <strong>Michigan </strong>baseball team heads to<strong> Northwestern </strong>on a hot streak, winning its last 10 games, including a no-hitter in an 8-2 victory against <strong>Notre Dame</strong> on Tuesday. It is the Wolverines longest winning streak since 2008 and has them in a tie for first place in the Big Ten standings. But maybe more exciting than Michigan&rsquo;s recent success, will be Saturday night&rsquo;s venue for the contest against the Wildcats, historic Wrigley Field. First pitch is at 7 p.m.</p>
<p>
	&quot;We&#39;re so grateful to the entire Chicago Cubs organization for opening the doors to this historic venue and for allowing Chicago&#39;s Big Ten Team to play a game at their beautiful facility,&quot; Northwestern head coach Paul Stevens said. &quot;Whether you grew up in Chicago or California, if you&#39;re a ballplayer, you&#39;ve dreamt of one day playing at Wrigley Field, one of the iconic sporting venues in the world. Northwestern and Michigan will get that chance on a very special night and we&#39;re all looking forward to the occasion.&quot;</p>
<div class="inline-left photo">
	<img src="/sites/default/files/images/penn-state-mgym.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 360px;" />
	<div class="photo-credit">
		<span>Penn State Athletics</span></div>
	<div class="photo-caption">
		Penn State enters the NCAA championships as the top-seed and will host the three-day competition.</div>
</div>
<div>
	<p>
		&bull; The<strong> Penn State</strong> men&rsquo;s gymnastics team spent the entire season at No. 1 in the national rankings, and will enter NCAA championships as the top-seeded team in a three-day event the Nittany Lions will host at the historic Recreation Building on the University Park campus beginning Friday. Penn State will not only be seeking its 13th NCAA title, but its first since 2007. The Nittany Lions will also be looking to rebound from a second-place finish at the Big Ten Championships on April 6, where <strong>No. 3 Michigan </strong>took the title. Penn State&rsquo;s <strong>Craig Hernandez</strong> leads the nation in the pommel horse with a 15.281 average, while <strong>Wasef Burbar </strong>is the top gymnast on the high bar with a 15.150 average.&nbsp;</p>
</div>
<p>
	&bull; The top two baseball teams in Division II&rsquo;s Mid-America Intercollegiate Athletic Association will meet for a three-game series beginning Saturday as<strong> No. 15 Central Missouri</strong> visits <strong>No. 5 Missouri Western</strong>. Missouri Western soared to No. 5 in the latest NCBWA poll after winning 29 of its last 31 games, including a 5-3 defeat of <strong>No. 4 St. Cloud State</strong> on Monday. It is the Griffons&rsquo; highest ranking in school history. Central Missouri sits in second place in the MIAA standings, and has won eight of its last 10 games.</p>
<p>
	&bull; After taking over the No. 1 spot in the latest Division III poll, <strong>Linfield</strong> will face a tough Northwest Conference test when the Wildcats host <strong>No. 18 George Fox</strong> in a battle of the league&rsquo;s top-two teams. George Fox currently holds a half-game lead against Linfield in the standings, and the outcome of the three-game series beginning Saturday will essentially determine the conference champion. The Wildcats have won four consecutive contests, and six of their last seven. Linfield ranks third nationally with a 2.32 ERA, and leads DIII with 34 double plays. The Bruins have also been hot, winning five of their last six games. They average 8.4 runs per game, which ranks 11th nationally.</p>
<p>
	&bull; The <strong>No. 8 Redlands </strong>softball squad enters the weekend on a 16-game winning streak, posting shutouts in its last four contests, and will look to cap off the regular season on high note as the Maroon and Gray visit <strong>No. 18 Claremont-Mudd-Scripps</strong> on Friday for a doubleheader in Division III&rsquo;s Southern California Intercollegiate Athletic Conference action. Redlands senior pitcher<strong> Kayla Uphold</strong> ranks 11th in the nation with a 1.08 ERA, and is third in DIII with 20 victories on the season. CMS has won six consecutive and shut out three of its last four opponents heading into the final weekend of the regular season.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/images/2011/Something_To_Talk_About.jpg" style="width: 630px; height: 50px; float: left;" /> &bull; The <strong>No. 15 Tampa </strong>softball team has been on fire, winning seven consecutive games with five shutouts during the stretch. Pitching has been an integral of the Spartans&rsquo; success, led by junior <strong>Kayla Cox</strong>. Cox has compiled a 19-4 record and 0.54 ERA, while striking out 246 batters in 155.2 innings pitched.&nbsp; She paces the nation in ERA, and ranks sixth in Division II with 11.1 strikeouts per seven innings. Cox also leads the nation in hits per seven innings (2.79) and shutouts (13).&nbsp; The Spartans look to extend their streak in a three-game series against Sunshine State Conference foe Nova Southeastern beginning Friday.</p>
<p>
	&bull; The <strong>No. 13 Indiana (Pa.) </strong>women&rsquo;s lacrosse team is off to the best start in program history after blasting off to a 10-0 mark and setting a school record for consecutive victories. IUP tops Division II with an 18.50 scoring average, led by <strong>Alexa Lodovici</strong>, who is contributing 4.0 goals and 3.3 assists per game. The Crimson Hawks are one of four Pennsylvania State Athletic Conference schools ranked in the national poll, and will host a pair of league foes this weekend. IUP will tangle with <strong>Kutztown</strong> on Friday, and then faces the other first-place team in the PSAC &ndash; <strong>No. 5 West Chester </strong>on Saturday. The Golden Rams and Crimson Hawks have identical 7-0 records in PSAC play.</p>
<p>
	&bull; In only its first season as a Division III program, the <strong>Mount Union</strong> women&rsquo;s lacrosse team is having a solid year. Since losing their season-opening contest to <strong>Oberlin </strong>by a one-goal margin, the Purple Raiders have been perfect, winning nine consecutive games. In seven of those nine victories, Mount Union has not given up more than four goals and has posted two shutouts. The Purple Raiders lead the nation in both scoring offense (18.70) and scoring defense (3.4) under first-year head coach <strong>Emily Fisher</strong>. Mount Union is playing as an independent in its first season, but next year the Ohio Athletic Conference will sponsor women&rsquo;s lacrosse. The Purple Raiders are in action on Friday when they host <strong>St. Vincent (Pa.)</strong>.</p>
<p>
	<em>Follow Amy Farnum on Twitter: @NCAA_Amy</em></p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/lacrosse-men/weekend-preview/2013-04-18/spring-postseason-approaches</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa">ncaa</category>
 <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-mens/lacrosse-men">lacrosse-men</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d1">d1</category>
 <category domain="/category/auto-created-vocabulary-2/ncaa">NCAA</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 16:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>lfarquhar</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">174263 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[No place like home]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>
	<strong>STATE COLLEGE, Pa. &ndash;</strong>- There are 12 &ndash; count &lsquo;em, 12, an even dozen &ndash; men&rsquo;s gymnastics national championship banners hanging from the rafters at Penn State.<br />
	<br />
	The oldest one dates all the way back to 1948 -- the first year the championships were held following World War II &ndash; and the newest to 2007. Although no other school has more men&rsquo;s gymnastics titles than Penn State, it&rsquo;s the white space on the walls that gets head coach Randy Jepson&rsquo;s attention.<br />
	<br />
	<table class="inline-left" style="width: 250px;">
	<thead>
		<tr>
			<th scope="col">
				2013 MEN&#39;S GYMNASTICS CHAMPIONSHIPS</th>
		</tr>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<strong>PREVIEW</strong></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Houston: <a href="/news/gymnastics-men/article/2013-04-18/no-place-home">No. 1 PSU hopes to hoist title at home</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				&bull; <a href="http://www.ncaa.com/news/gymnastics-men/article/2013-04-09/2013-mens-gymnastics-championship-qualifier-selections-announ">Championship qualifiers announced</a></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				More: <a href="http://www.ncaa.com/championships/gymnastics-men/d1">Championship Information</a> | <a href="http://www.ncaa.com/history/gymnastics-men/nc">History</a></td>
		</tr>
	</tbody>
</table>That&rsquo;s where the next championship banners will go. It&rsquo;s a sermon that Jepson preaches every year on the first day of practice. There are expectations to be met, so go out and meet them.<br />
	<br />
	&ldquo;That&rsquo;s why they come to school at Penn State to do gymnastics -&ndash; to try to achieve at that level,&rdquo; Jepson said. &ldquo;But what I have them focus on is not just the championships that are hung on the wall, it&rsquo;s the empty space that remains. That&rsquo;s what they are to fill. That&rsquo;s their stage and what they work for and what they do that will determine whether they get to hang a banner or not.&rdquo;<br />
	<br />
	Penn State is ranked first in the nation going into this weekend&rsquo;s national championship meet at &hellip; yes &hellip; Penn State&rsquo;s Rec Hall. The last time school competed for the sport&rsquo;s biggest prize on its home turf was in 2007, so it&rsquo;s hard not to like its chances.<br />
	<br />
	It&rsquo;s obvious that Jepson&rsquo;s student-athletes will have support so close to home, but he also points out that in order to safeguard them, he&rsquo;s asked that they keep contact with friends and family to a minimum. Because of the team&rsquo;s success this year, Jepson also doesn&rsquo;t want to change the way it goes about its business.<br />
	<br />
	&ldquo;Another thing that we want to do is just make sure they keep their own routine,&rdquo; Jepson continued. &ldquo;That&rsquo;s one advantage of being at home. You don&rsquo;t have travel situations or hotels and whatnot. We try to take it as a positive, if we can.&rdquo;<br />
	<br />
	Jepson is cautiously optimistic going into the meet, but he&rsquo;s certainly not foolish enough to guarantee a victory over any of the other elite squads that will be competing this weekend. The Nittany Lions may be ranked first in the nation going into the title weekend, but they also lost out on the Big Ten championship to Michigan a couple of weeks ago.<br />
	<br />
	The game plan is simple. Don&rsquo;t pay attention to the rankings and expect to meet teams that as formidable as they are &ndash;- if not more so.<br />
	<br />
	&ldquo;We know that we can go in and have a great meet, and if that&rsquo;s enough to win, great,&rdquo; Jepson explained. &ldquo;We can also go in and have a very difficult time of things and really struggle. So you have to be ready to do the job, not matter what.<br />
	<br />
	&ldquo;Nothing will be given to you. Everything has to be earned. The ranking really goes out the window at this point, and it&rsquo;s down to a toe-to-toe, knock-down, drag-out weekend.&rdquo;<br />
	<br />
	Penn State&rsquo;s gymnasts, says Jepson, are very good on the pommel horse and rings. At the same time however, it&rsquo;s sometimes touch-and-go on how well they perform on the parallel bars and floor routines.<br />
	<br />
	Just behind Penn State in qualifying scores are Oklahoma, Michigan, Stanford and Ohio State, followed by Minnesota, Illinois, Iowa, California and Nebraska in the top 10. Air Force and Temple also qualified for the meet.<br />
	<br />
	On any given weekend, any of them would stand a very real chance of winning. With so much on the line here, who knows what might happen?<br />
	<br />
	&ldquo;There&rsquo;s some very, very good teams here,&rdquo; Jepson said. &ldquo;We can&rsquo;t beat ourselves. If we have some mistakes, it&rsquo;s going to be the end of the championship quest. So we&rsquo;ve got to be healthy, be focused and be really consistent throughout the competition.&rdquo;<br />
	<br />
	And one other thing &hellip;<br />
	<br />
	&ldquo;Number two, we&rsquo;ve got to not just get through, but really excel,&rdquo; he added. &ldquo;Our best guys have to come through and we have to set good scores up at the beginning of each rotation. So it will be a total team effort. We&rsquo;ve got a very tough task ahead of us.&rdquo;<br />
	<br />
	Jepson has been a part of the Penn State landscape for years. A 1982 graduate, he began as assistant under the long-time men&rsquo;s gymnastics head coach Karl Schier the following season. Jepson then took over the top spot in 1992 upon Schier&rsquo;s retirement.<br />
	<br />
	What would it mean to Jepson to do well? That&rsquo;s an easy one.<br />
	<br />
	&ldquo;We would love to have a very sound and solid performance as a team,&rdquo; he concluded. &ldquo;We&rsquo;ve pulled together a group of guys who started four years ago as freshmen who were very unheralded. Now that they&rsquo;re seniors, they would like to go out with a great showing.<br />
	<br />
	&ldquo;This group of guys is really near and dear to my heart. I&rsquo;ve won other championships with other teams. This team hasn&rsquo;t. It would be just a wonderful thing to see them pull off a championship in a home situation here.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	<em>For the latest updates and tweets from the Men&rsquo;s Gymnastics Championships please search on Twitter with #ncaamgym.</em></p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/gymnastics-men/article/2013-04-18/no-place-home</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-mens/gymnastics-men">gymnastics-men</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d1">d1</category>
 <category domain="/category/auto-created-vocabulary-2/ncaa">NCAA</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/pennsylvania-state-university">Pennsylvania State University</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 14:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>mspoor</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">174255 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Humbling season for Garrido, Texas]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>
	Augie Garrido says, maybe only half-jokingly, that he needs to be fitted for a miner&#39;s cap the way the baseball season is going for Texas.</p>
<p>
	&#39;&#39;It&#39;s dark down here where I&#39;m at,&#39;&#39; he said.</p>
<p>
	The Longhorns are tied for last in the Big 12, unfamiliar territory for a program that has made a record 34 College World Series appearances and is headed by the coach with the most wins in Division I history. No Texas baseball team has finished at the bottom of its league since 1956.</p>
<p>
	The struggle is excruciating, and not just because the Longhorns are losing so many close games. The annual expectation is to end the season in Omaha, Neb., at the CWS -- something the Longhorns have done seven times since 2000. Each time they make it, Garrido unfailingly says it&#39;s as much a relief as an accomplishment.</p>
<p>
	The CWS is a long shot this year. With a month left in the regular season, the Longhorns have a lot of work to do just to avoid missing the NCAA tournament in consecutive years for the first time since 1997-98.</p>
<table class="inline-left" style="width: 250px;">
	<caption>
		Augie Garrido at Texas</caption>
	<thead>
		<tr>
			<th scope="col">
				Year</th>
			<th scope="col">
				Record</th>
			<th scope="col">
				Finish</th>
		</tr>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
		<tr>
			<td>
				1997</td>
			<td>
				29-22</td>
			<td>
				No Postseason</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				1998</td>
			<td>
				23-32-1</td>
			<td>
				No Postseason</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				1999</td>
			<td>
				36-26</td>
			<td>
				Houston Regional</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				2000</td>
			<td>
				46-21</td>
			<td>
				College World Series</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				2001</td>
			<td>
				36-26</td>
			<td>
				Palo Alto Regional</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				2002</td>
			<td>
				57-15</td>
			<td>
				National Champions</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				2003</td>
			<td>
				50-20</td>
			<td>
				College World Series</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				2004</td>
			<td>
				58-15</td>
			<td>
				College World Series</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				2005</td>
			<td>
				56-16</td>
			<td>
				National Champions</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				2006</td>
			<td>
				41-21</td>
			<td>
				Austin Regional</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				2007</td>
			<td>
				46-17</td>
			<td>
				Round Rock Regional</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				2008</td>
			<td>
				39-22</td>
			<td>
				Houston Regional</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				2009</td>
			<td>
				50-16-1</td>
			<td>
				College World Series</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				2010</td>
			<td>
				50-13</td>
			<td>
				Austin Super Regional</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				2011</td>
			<td>
				49-19</td>
			<td>
				College World Series</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				2012</td>
			<td>
				30-22</td>
			<td>
				Big 12 Tournament</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				2013</td>
			<td>
				20-15</td>
			<td>
				TBD</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<strong>Total</strong></td>
			<td colspan="2" rowspan="1">
				716-338-2</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td colspan="3">
				<em>*Record as of April 18</em>.</td>
		</tr>
	</tbody>
</table>
<p>
	They&#39;ve lost seven consecutive Big 12 series going back to last season as they head into a three-game set against West Virginia. They&#39;re 20-15 overall after Tuesday&#39;s 6-1 non-conference win against Texas-Pan American, but just 4-8 in the Big 12.</p>
<p>
	Of their 35 games, 23 have been decided by two runs or less. They&#39;re 9-7 in one-run games.</p>
<p>
	&#39;&#39;They&#39;ve lost some close games, and they probably don&#39;t have the talent top to bottom that you would normally have at Texas,&#39;&#39; said Stanford coach Mark Marquess, whose team has played a series against the Longhorns every season since 1998 and swept their three games last month.</p>
<p>
	The pitching has more than held up its end, but the defense has been spotty and the Longhorns have been unable to get timely hitting.</p>
<p>
	The Longhorns are averaging just 2.8 runs in Big 12 games, well below the 5.1 of last season. They&#39;re batting .246 in conference games and just .164 with runners in scoring position.</p>
<p>
	The bright spots have been right fielder Mark Payton, who&#39;s batting .400 and is bidding to become Texas&#39; first player to end the season at that hallowed mark since 2002, and third baseman Erich Weiss, who&#39;s batting .388 in Big 12 games.</p>
<p>
	Take Payton and Weiss out of the mix, though, and the Longhorns&#39; overall average drops 27 points to .239.</p>
<p>
	Top starting pitchers Parker French (3-2), Dillon Peters (3-2) and Nathan Thornhill (2-4) all have ERAs of 2.77 or better, and the staff started the week 17th nationally at 2.68. Star closer Corey Knebel has seven saves and 35 for his career, six behind the school record set by Huston Street from 2002-04. But Knebel didn&#39;t help matters last weekend when he was sent back to Austin during the series at Kansas because of a violation of team rules. Garrido reinstated him Monday.</p>
<p>
	Defensive problems revealed themselves in a big way in the sixth inning of Sunday&#39;s 4-3 loss.</p>
<p>
	The Jayhawks&#39; Tucker Tharp reached after Ty Marlow dropped second baseman Brooks Marlow&#39;s short flip on what should have been an easy out at first. The next batter bunted, and catcher Jacob Felts tried to get the lead runner at second. But Felts&#39; low throw went into center field and Tharp ended up on third. The next batter hit a ball at shortstop C.J. Hinojosa, who bobbled it and had to settle for getting the runner at second instead of trying to throw home to get Tharp, who scored the winning run.</p>
<p>
	&#39;&#39;So the same guy was out three times,&#39;&#39; Garrido said, &#39;&#39;but scored a run.&#39;&#39;</p>
<p>
	Though Hinojosa has committed 10 errors, most of any shortstop in the Big 12, Garrido said the infield has generally excelled.</p>
<p>
	&#39;&#39;That&#39;s what is probably the most gut-wrenching and heart-breaking for everyone on the team,&#39;&#39; Garrido said. &#39;&#39;We can look out on the field and know that we are so close to being a championship-type team, and at the same time we&#39;re so far away from that in reality.&#39;&#39;</p>
<p>
	Texas had chances to tie after falling behind in that last game against Kansas, but a runner was thrown out at home to end the seventh inning, and the Longhorns couldn&#39;t score after having a runner at second base with one in both the eighth and ninth.</p>
<p>
	&#39;&#39;We&#39;ve mastered the art of losing,&#39;&#39; said Garrido, who said his team&#39;s &#39;&#39;confidence factor is not overcoming the fear factor.&#39;&#39;</p>
<p>
	Stanford&#39;s Marquess said Texas is no different from other elite programs that have struggled. He pointed out that everyone in college baseball was in shock when LSU didn&#39;t make the NCAA tournament in 2011, two years after winning the national championship. Florida, coming off three consecutive CWS appearances, is just over .500. Same with Miami (Fla.), which once was a CWS regular but hasn&#39;t been to Omaha since 2008.</p>
<p>
	&#39;&#39;It&#39;s not unique to Texas. It&#39;s just a different time,&#39;&#39; Marquess said. &#39;&#39;And the problem is the expectation level for those elite programs and their fans is unrealistic, to be honest. It can&#39;t be like it used to be. You can&#39;t dominate. There are no guaranteed wins anymore.&#39;&#39;</p>
<p>
	College baseball&#39;s parity and the struggles of his Longhorns haven&#39;t diminished the 74-year-old Garrido&#39;s enthusiasm for his job. He hears the grumbling of the fans, which he said is to be expected in a program that has a passionate following.</p>
<p>
	His contract runs through 2015, and he&#39;s paid $985,000 a year. He has no plans to retire, though he acknowledges he serves at the administration&#39;s pleasure.</p>
<p>
	&#39;&#39;I don&#39;t have a lot of hobbies. I don&#39;t have other things I like to do,&#39;&#39; he said. &#39;&#39;I&#39;m totally all in with this.&#39;&#39;<br />
	&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/baseball/article/2013-04-18/humbling-season-garrido-texas</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-mens/baseball">baseball</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d1">d1</category>
 <category domain="/category/auto-created-vocabulary-2/ap">AP</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/university-texas-austin">University of Texas at Austin</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 14:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>dkroll</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">174251 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Wake Forest to donate proceeds from weekend to Boston bombing victims]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>
	<strong>WINSTON-SALEM, N.C. -- </strong>Wake Forest says it is donating the ticket proceeds from it weekend baseball series against Boston College to a fund to help families affected by the Boston Marathon bombing.</p>
<p>
	School officials said Wednesday that the proceeds will go to The One Fund Boston. It was created by Massachusetts Gov. Deval Patrick and Boston Mayor Tom Menino.</p>
<p>
	The school also says it will have staff members on hand to accept donations from fans.</p>
<p>
	There are four players on the Demon Deacons&#39; roster from the Boston area, and coach Tom Walter says &#39;&#39;our team feels a connection with the Boston College team and the city of Boston.&#39;&#39;</p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/baseball/article/2013-04-18/wake-forest-donate-proceeds-weekend-boston-bombing-victims</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-mens/baseball">baseball</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d1">d1</category>
 <category domain="/category/auto-created-vocabulary-2/ap">AP</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/boston-college">Boston College</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/wake-forest-university">Wake Forest University</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 14:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>dkroll</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">174247 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Kansas to build $18M facility to house Naismith's original rules of basketball]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>
	<strong>LAWRENCE, Kan.&nbsp;</strong> -- James Naismith&#39;s original rules of basketball are about to have a permanent home.</p>
<p>
	Appropriately enough, right on Naismith Drive.</p>
<p>
	The University of Kansas plans to build an $18 million facility that connects to Allen Fieldhouse and will house the original two-page document on which, in 1891, Naismith outlined the 13 basic rules for what would become the game of basketball.</p>
<p>
	The three-story facility will be known as the DeBruce Center in honor of Paul and Katherine DeBruce, who donated the bulk of the private funding. Along with housing the rules, it will have dining and meeting spaces available for students, faculty and visitors.</p>
<p>
	Construction is expected to begin later this year.</p>
<p>
	&#39;&#39;The DeBruce Center will serve not only as a &#39;must-see&#39; destination landmark for sports fans and history buffs, but also as an important, integral part of campus benefiting students, faculty and visitors alike,&#39;&#39; Kansas athletic director Sheahon Zenger said Wednesday.</p>
<p>
	In 2010, Kansas alumnus David Booth purchased Naismith&#39;s original rules at an auction for $4.3 million, at the time the highest price paid for sports memorabilia.</p>
<p>
	Booth&#39;s intention was for the rules to reside at Kansas, where Naismith founded the school&#39;s basketball program in 1898 and then spent nine years as its coach. The story of Booth&#39;s purchase was detailed in an ESPN &#39;&#39;30 for 30&#39;&#39; documentary, &#39;&#39;There&#39;s No Place Like Home.&#39;&#39;</p>
<p>
	The acquisition of the rules became the catalyst for a new building on campus.</p>
<p>
	&#39;&#39;Our years on the Hill helped provide a foundation for each of us to be successful and give back to our community,&#39;&#39; said Paul DeBruce, who founded a grain company in the late 1970s.</p>
<p>
	&#39;&#39;Part of that experience was academic,&#39;&#39; DeBruce said, &#39;&#39;but a lot of it included the many friends we made there and the fond memories of attending basketball games at Allen Fieldhouse. We hope the new center will be a place on campus that students and faculty will want to come to and enjoy. It will be a meeting place for friends and a place to further honor KU traditions.&#39;&#39;<br />
	&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
    <link>http://ncaa.com/news/basketball-men/article/2013-04-18/kansas-build-18m-facility-house-naismiths-original-rules-bask</link>
     <category domain="/category/sport/ncaa-mens/basketball-men">basketball-men</category>
 <category domain="/category/division/d1">d1</category>
 <category domain="/category/auto-created-vocabulary-2/ap">AP</category>
 <category domain="/category/schools0/university-kansas">University of Kansas</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 14:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>mspoor</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">174243 at </guid>
  </item>  </channel>
</rss>